Hello and welcome to Real easyy English from BBC Learning English This is the podcast where we have real conversations in easy English to help you with
Your learning I'm Becca and I'm Phil and you can watch a video version of this podcast on our website it's got subtitles to help you learn that's BBClearningenglish.com. .
How are you today Phil I'm good I'm really good What about you have you got any plans for this week coming up Yes I'm really excited for the weekend because I'm going
To meet up with some of my old school friends I've known them since I was in year eight Wellcca today we're talking about old friends
And when we say old friends we mean friends that we've had a long time particularly since we were children So Phil do you have.
Many old friends yeah, I do have some, but I probably don't see them as much as I should why is that as you get older, you move away, you have families, you.
And I'm just not very good at staying in touch with people, so I don't often see people that are very old friends.
What about you do you have many old friends that you see often Yeah I do, I do, I mean luckily for myself, we don't live very far away.
So it is easier to stay in touch and by staying in touch we mean kind of keeping that contact, so I do have a couple of friendship groups.
We have group chats where we kind of, you know, keep in touch with each other there and we plan meetings,
Although we find that when we plan to meet each other, we will then, Plan to meet each other the next time,
Months in advance, months before we meet because yeah, it is difficult when you are older and you get busy.
How often do you see your old friends it sounds like you stay in touch quite a lot Yeah, we do, we stay in touch a lot over like I said group chat,
Social media and we try to meet, At least once every month, once every couple of months,
You know, if we really try, so yeah it is easier for us to meet up so when when was the last time that you saw one of your old friends,
It was probably sometime last year, I think, but yeah, I probably only only a couple of times a year, I think I'd see old friends and have you lost touch with any of your
Old friends so to lose touches to lose that?
Contact that you have with them Yes, I think I have you don't notice it when it happens, do you really because its it's not like you have an argument.
Or you say I'm not talking to that person anymore, you you just I don't know, you just don't see them for a long time,
If I saw those people again, then I might get back in touch with them, but yeah there's there's people that,
There's definitely people that I used to know that I haven't seen for a long time, so yeah, I've definitely lost touch with some people so do you think your Friendship?
Groups have kind of changed as you've grown older then if you've lost touch with some old friends, you have newer friends now, what has changed a lot is I have.
A lot more friends who are families who have children the same age that we have because suddenly when you have children,
You have so much in common with people in the same situation and your children do.
And if your children get on very well together, you're going to spend a lot of time together, I see, so that's where we're quite different because a lot of my friends don't have families and.
You know, I don't either, so it's quite easy for us to stay friends and to stay in touch with each other.
Okay, let's recap some of the vocabulary we learned in this episode starting with Old friend and that's a friend that you've known for a very long time So we had this idea
Of being in touch with someone.
With a friend and if you are in touch with someone, it means that you see them often you speak to them often,
So if you keep in touch with someone, it means you continue to do those things even after a long time.
If you lose touch with someone, that means that you don't see or speak to them anymore.
However you can get back in touch with someone that is to start seeing them or speaking to them again and if you stay friends with someone it means
That you continue to be friends for a long of time example it's easy for me to stay friends with some of my because we very
Other's it for this of real the works on,
Website BBC Learning English.com. to practice and to help you have your own easy English conversations and we'll be back next week with another real conversation in easy English
But for now it's goodbye bye.